Inventory of Presidents' Papers, Papers of Richard A. Gleeson, S.J., 1905-1910
University Archives
Inventory of Presidents' Papers, Papers of Richard A. Gleeson, S.J.,
1905-1910
3DB13
989-051
Gleeson, Richard A., S.J.
5 folders
Santa Clara University Archives Santa Clara, CA 95053
Administrative Information
Access
Santa Clara University permits public access to its archives within the context of respect for individual privacy, administrative confidentiality, and the integrity of the records. It reserves the right to close all or any portion of its records to researchers.
The archival files of any office may be opened to a qualified researcher by the administrator of that office or his/her designee at any time.
Archival collections may be used by researchers only in the Reading Room of the University Archives and may be photocopied only at the discretion of the archivist.
Biographical Note
Gleeson was the 13th president of Santa Clara College, whose term as president was characterized by his efforts at fundraising for the college.
Scope and Content
The Gleeson Papers include correspondence and fund raising materials for the proposed plan to move Santa Clara College to Mountain View. Also includes correspondence regarding the 1909 fire on campus, and biographical information about Gleeson.
Container List
- FIRE OF 1909 AND SUBSEQUENT FUND RAISING
  - Note on fire insurance for the Faculty Residence received after the 1909 fire. (Folder 1)
  - Souvenir Program: "All honor to the valiant rescuers of the Old Misssion[sic] Church." Program for banquet given by the S.C. faculty to thank the fire fighters, Jan. 18, 1910.
  - Correspondence:
    - To "Dear Friend" from The Executive Committee of S.C.U. Building Collectors, May 19, 1910. (3 copies)
    - To Gleeson from J.P. Campbell re the fire of 1909, Dec. 24, 1909.
    - To Gleeson from Archbishop Riordan expressing his sympathy about the fire, Dec. 22, 1909.
    - To Gleeson from Archbishop Riordan re removal of Santa Clara College to Loyola Corners, Jan. 25, 1910.
    - To Gleeson from Archbishop Riordan re his donation to the building fund, Jan 26, 1910.
    - To Rev. Joseph Sasia, S.J., from Archbishop Riordan re the letter he wrote for Gleeson to help him collect funds for the new Santa Clara College, Jan. 26, 1910.
    - To Gleeson from J.M. O'Hara, J.M. re his inability to contribute to S.C., April 26, 1910.
    - Telegram to Gleeson from Palomares, Frank re the "Campaign to Raise $50,000", April 8, 1910.
  - Pamphlet: "The University of Santa Clara which will succeed Santa Clara College at Loyola, near Mountain View, Santa Clara County, Needs and Seeks Generous Benefactors." n.d. [1910]. 5 copies.
  - Open letter (printed): To Gleeson from Riordan, re support for fund-raising for new college, Jan. 25, 1910.
- LOANS
  - Ledgers documenting loans taken out against "Building Fund Money" by faculty and staff, ca. 1909. 2 pages. (Folder 2)
  - Reciepts and loan instruments. 1907-1910. (Folder 3)
- TUITION AND FEES
  - Correspondence to Gleeson from G.B. Raffeto re his son's tuition rates, Aug. 4, 1906. (Folder 4)
- BIOGRAPHICAL
  - Letter to Mrs. [Mary] Wempe from Mrs. Eustace Cullinan of the Woman's Committee re building of the Richard A. Gleeson Library Building at the University of San Francisco. 1940. 1 page." (Folder 5)